export const cryptoGlossary: {
    [key: string]: {
        question: string;
        answer: string;
    }[]
}[] = [
        {
            "A": [
                {
                    question: "Address",
                    answer: "A place where cryptocurrency can be sent to and from, in the form of a string of letters and numbers. A cryptocurrency address can be shared publicly in the form of text or QR code to those who want to send you cryptocurrency."
                },
                {
                    question: "Airdrop",
                    answer: "A marketing campaign that distributes a specific cryptocurrency or token to an audience. It is usually initiated by the creator of a cryptocurrency in order to encourage use and build popularity of the coin or token. Most airdrop campaigns run with mechanics such as receiving coins or tokens in exchange for simple tasks like sharing news, referring friends or downloading an app."
                },
                {
                    question: "Algorithm",
                    answer: "A process or set of rules to be followed in problem-solving or calculation operations, usually by a computer, although humans tend to follow steps algorithmically as well (let's say doing math or following a recipe)."
                },
                {
                    question: "All-Time-High (ATH)",
                    answer: "The highest point (in price, in market capitalization) that a cryptocurrency has been in history."
                },
                {
                    question: "All-Time-Low (ATL)",
                    answer: "The lowest point (in price, in market capitalization) that a cryptocurrency has been in history."
                },
                {
                    question: "Altcoin",
                    answer: "As Bitcoin is the first cryptocurrency that captured the world's imagination, all other coins were subsequently termed \"altcoins,\" as in \"alternative coins.\""
                },
                {
                    question: "Anarcho-capitalism",
                    answer: "A political philosophy and school of thought that believes in removing centralized states in favor of self-ownership, private property and free markets. Many of the early adopters of Bitcoin were proponents of anarcho-capitalism, believing it would give power and control back to the masses."
                },
                {
                    question: "Anti-Money Laundering (AML)",
                    answer: "A set of international laws enacted to curtail criminal organizations or individuals laundering money through cryptocurrencies into real-world cash."
                },
                {
                    question: "API",
                    answer: "API stands for Application Programming Interface. It is a set of routines, protocols, and tools for building software applications. APIs specify how software components should interact, such as what data to use and what actions should be taken."
                },
                {
                    question: "Arbitrage",
                    answer: "A practice of taking advantage of differences in price of the same commodity in two or more markets or exchanges. For example, cryptocurrency prices on Korean exchanges can be different from those on US exchanges. An arbitrage trader would be in both markets in order to buy in one and sell in another for profit."
                },
                {
                    question: "Ashdraked",
                    answer: "A situation where you lose all your money, more specifically when you lose all your money shorting Bitcoin. This was based on a story of a Romanian trader who continued to short BTC when it went from $300 to $500, since he had made a lot of profit doing so historically. Adapt your trading strategy!"
                },
                {
                    question: "ASIC",
                    answer: "Short for \"Application Specific Integrated Circuit\"; it is a mining equipment that is used specifically to mine a certain cryptocurrency. Often compared to GPUs, ASICs are specially created and bought for mining purposes and offer significant efficiency improvements and power savings due to its narrow use case."
                },
                {
                    question: "Ask Price",
                    answer: "In any financial market, buyers and sellers place their orders to determine the highest price they are willing to buy and the lowest price they are willing to sell. The buyers place \"bids\" and sellers place \"asks,\" or offers to sell. If a \"bid\" is higher than an \"ask,\" a trade occurs, as the buyer is willing to pay more than what the seller wants. At any given point in time, the lowest ask order that is unmatched becomes the \"Ask Price\" of the market."
                },
                {
                    question: "Astroturfing",
                    answer: "A deceptive practice where a sponsor is masked or hidden, making it seem as though a marketing message came from and is strongly supported by the community when it is not."
                },
                {
                    question: "Atomic Swap",
                    answer: "A way of letting people directly exchange one type of cryptocurrency for another on a different blockchain or off-chain without a centralized intermediary such as an exchange."
                },
                {
                    question: "Attestation Ledger",
                    answer: "An attestation ledger is an account book designed to provide evidence of individual transactions. It is generally used to \"attest\" that a financial transaction took place, or to prove authenticity of transactions or products."
                }
            ]
        },

        {
            "B": [
                {
                    question: "Bag",
                    answer: "A significant quantity of a specific cryptocurrency is considered a \"bag.\" How many depends on the definition of the person using the expression. *see Bagholder."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bagholder",
                    answer: "A person who holds large quantities, or bags, of a cryptocurrency. Often used to describe such a person when the price of that cryptocurrency is declining."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bear",
                    answer: "A person who is pessimistic about market prices and expects them to decline. This person is also known to be \"bearish\" about the market or price. *see Bull."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bear Trap",
                    answer: "A technique played by a group of traders, aimed at manipulating the price of a cryptocurrency. The bear trap is set by selling a large amount of the same cryptocurrency at the same time, fooling the market into thinking there is an upcoming price decline. In response, other traders sell their assets, further driving the price down. Those who set the trap then release it, buying back their assets at a lower price. The price then rebounds, allowing them to make a profit."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bitcoin ATM (BTM)",
                    answer: "A machine from which you can withdraw bitcoin."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP)",
                    answer: "A technical design document providing information to the Bitcoin community, describing new proposed features, processes or environments affecting the Bitcoin protocol. Suggested changes to the protocol are submitted as a BIP. The BIP author is responsible for soliciting feedback and consensus for his or her suggested improvements within the community, and documenting dissenting opinions."
                },
                {
                    question: "BitLicense",
                    answer: "A business license issued to cryptocurrency companies in New York, created and provided by the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYSDFS)."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bits",
                    answer: "A sub-unit of one bitcoin. There are 1,000,000 bits in one bitcoin."
                },
                {
                    question: "Block",
                    answer: "A container or collection of transactions occurring every time period on a blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Blockchain",
                    answer: "A blockchain is a continuously growing, append-only, list of records called blocks, which are linked and secured using cryptography."
                },
                {
                    question: "Block Explorer",
                    answer: "An online tool to view all transactions that has taken place on the blockchain, network hash rate and transaction growth, among other useful information."
                },
                {
                    question: "Block Height",
                    answer: "The number of blocks preceding the block in question on the blockchain, or can be thought of as total blocks in the chain before this point."
                },
                {
                    question: "Block Reward",
                    answer: "An incentive for a miner who successfully calculates a valid hash in a block during mining. By contributing to the security and liveness of the chain, the miner is rewarded with this incentive, ensuring that miners continue to act in the best interest of the blockchain by legitimately taking part in the process (instead of hacking it)."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bollinger Band",
                    answer: "A tool developed by Bollinger to help in the recognition of systemic pattern recognition in prices; it is a band that is plotted two standard deviations away from the simple moving average, or exponential moving average in some cases."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bots",
                    answer: "Automated trading software that executes buy-and-sell orders quickly based on preset algorithms."
                },
                {
                    question: "Brute Force Attack (BFA)",
                    answer: "A trial-and-error method where automated software generates numerous combinations to crack codes or keys."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bubble",
                    answer: "A market situation where prices rise excessively above their value, often followed by a rapid price drop as the market corrects."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bug Bounty",
                    answer: "Rewards offered by companies (like protocols, exchanges, or wallets) for identifying vulnerabilities in their systems before exploitation."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bull",
                    answer: "An investor optimistic about rising market prices, also referred to as being 'bullish.'"
                },
                {
                    question: "Bull Trap",
                    answer: "A false signal suggesting an upward trend in a declining asset, leading investors to lose money when the trend doesn't materialize."
                },
                {
                    question: "Buy The Dip (BTD/BTFD)",
                    answer: "An enthusiastic call to purchase cryptocurrency during a price drop."
                },
                {
                    question: "Buy Wall",
                    answer: "A large buy order at a specific price to prevent a cryptocurrency's value from falling below that point."
                },
                {
                    question: "Burned",
                    answer: "Tokens or coins permanently removed from circulation and made unusable."
                },
                {
                    question: "Byzantine Generals’ Problem",
                    answer: "A challenge in distributed systems where consensus is required despite untrustworthy participants or false communication."
                },
                {
                    question: "Byzantine Fault Tolerance (BFT)",
                    answer: "A property of systems like Bitcoin that reach consensus despite failures or imperfect information, often through mechanisms like proof-of-work."
                },
            ]
        },

        {
            "C": [
                {
                    question: "Candlesticks",
                    answer: "A charting technique showing price changes over time, with each candle providing opening, closing, high, and low prices."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cash",
                    answer: "The physical form of currency, including banknotes and coins."
                },
                {
                    question: "Centralized",
                    answer: "A network or system controlled by a small group of nodes or entities."
                },
                {
                    question: "Central Ledger",
                    answer: "A transaction record maintained by a centralized authority, such as a bank."
                },
                {
                    question: "Central Processing Unit (CPU)",
                    answer: "The CPU, or Central Processing Unit, is the 'brain' of a computer, coordinating different components running on a computer. Its speed is measured in gigahertz (GHz)."
                },
                {
                    question: "Change in Bitcoin",
                    answer: "Bitcoin transactions are composed of inputs and outputs in a system called Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO). When you send bitcoins, the full output is used, and the remaining amount is sent back as change."
                },
                {
                    question: "Chargeback",
                    answer: "A demand by a credit-card provider for a retailer to reimburse a fraudulent or disputed transaction, reversing the authorized payment or transfer."
                },
                {
                    question: "Chain Split",
                    answer: "Another term used to describe a Fork in a blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cipher",
                    answer: "The algorithm used to encrypt and decrypt information."
                },
                {
                    question: "Circulating",
                    answer: "The best approximation of the number of coins circulating in the market and in the general public's hands. *See Max Supply and Total Supply."
                },
                {
                    question: "Client",
                    answer: "Software that can access and process blockchain transactions on a local computer, such as a cryptocurrency software wallet."
                },
                {
                    question: "Close",
                    answer: "The closing price of an asset, similar to the term used in financial stocks."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cloud Mining",
                    answer: "Mining cryptocurrency using remote processing power rented from companies in regions with cost-efficient electricity and cold temperatures. Also called mining contracts."
                },
                {
                    question: "Coin",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency that can operate independently."
                },
                {
                    question: "Bitcoin",
                    answer: "A required transaction in a block that directs where the mining reward is sent. It includes a 100-byte size input, which can store messages or be used as an extra nonce."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cold Storage",
                    answer: "Offline storage of cryptocurrencies using hardware wallets, USB drives, offline computers, or paper wallets. *See Hot Storage."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cold Wallet",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency wallet kept offline, typically used for cold storage."
                },
                {
                    question: "Confirmations",
                    answer: "A transaction is confirmed when included in a block on the blockchain, and each subsequent block adds an additional confirmation."
                },
                {
                    question: "Consensus",
                    answer: "When all network participants agree on the order and content of blocks and transactions in a blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Consortium Blockchain",
                    answer: "A private blockchain operated by a consortium, sharing information selectively while leveraging blockchain's transparency and immutability."
                },
                {
                    question: "Correction",
                    answer: "A reverse market movement of at least 10% to adjust for over- or under-valuations."
                },
                {
                    question: "Co-Signer",
                    answer: "A person or entity with partial control and access to a cryptocurrency wallet."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cryptoasset",
                    answer: "Assets that use cryptography, consensus algorithms, distributed ledgers, and smart contracts for value storage, exchange, or decentralized applications."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cryptocurrency",
                    answer: "A digital medium of exchange secured by cryptography to facilitate financial transactions and asset transfers."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cryptography",
                    answer: "The study and practice of securing information to prevent unauthorized access."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cryptographic Hash Function",
                    answer: "A function that produces a fixed-size and unique hash value from variable-size input. The SHA-256 algorithm is a common example."
                },
                {
                    question: "Crypto-jacking",
                    answer: "Unauthorized use of someone else's computer to mine cryptocurrency."
                },
                {
                    question: "Custodial",
                    answer: "A setup where private keys are held by a service provider, allowing users to access their wallets via login credentials. *See Non-custodial."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cypherpunk",
                    answer: "An activist advocating for strong cryptographic and privacy-enhancing technologies to drive social and political progress."
                }
            ]
        },

        {
            "D": [
                {
                    question: "Dark Web",
                    answer: "A part of the internet not indexed by search engines, accessible only with specialized software, configurations, or authorizations."
                },
                {
                    question: "Date of Launch",
                    answer: "The term used to denote when ICOs make their tokens available for sale."
                },
                {
                    question: "Dead Cat Bounce",
                    answer: "A temporary recovery in prices following a significant decrease."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized",
                    answer: "Decentralization refers to a system in which nodes or actors work in a distributed fashion to achieve a global goal without relying on a central authority."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized Applications (DApps)",
                    answer: "Applications that run on a decentralized network, avoiding a single point of failure."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized Autonomous Initial Coin Offerings (DAICO)",
                    answer: "A decentralized funding method combining ideas from DAOs and ICOs, proposed by Vitalik Buterin, allowing backers to vote for fund returns if conditions are unmet."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAO)",
                    answer: "Organizations managed through rules encoded in smart contracts, without traditional central governance."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized Exchange (DEX)",
                    answer: "A peer-to-peer platform for buying and selling cryptocurrency without a central intermediary."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decryption",
                    answer: "The process of transforming encrypted data back into its original, readable form."
                },
                {
                    question: "DeFi",
                    answer: "DeFi, or decentralized finance, is an ecosystem of financial tools built on blockchain, offering open and permissionless alternatives to traditional financial services."
                },
                {
                    question: "Deflation",
                    answer: "A reduction in the general level of prices in an economy, or a monetary policy where the supply of currency or assets is fixed, like Bitcoin."
                },
                {
                    question: "Delegated Proof-of-Stake (dPOS)",
                    answer: "A consensus mechanism where users vote for delegates who produce blocks, with votes proportional to their stake, improving efficiency and reducing environmental impact."
                },
                {
                    question: "Depth Chart",
                    answer: "A graph showing buy (bids) and sell (asks) requests on a chart based on limit orders, indicating where transactions are likely to occur."
                },
                {
                    question: "Derivative",
                    answer: "A contract deriving its value from the performance of an underlying asset, index, or interest rate."
                },
                {
                    question: "Derivatives Market",
                    answer: "A public market for trading derivatives, such as futures contracts or options, based on other cryptocurrency assets."
                },
                {
                    question: "Deterministic Wallet",
                    answer: "A wallet that derives keys from a seed, allowing users to back up and restore the wallet using the same seed. *See Hierarchical Deterministic Wallet (HD Wallet)."
                },
                {
                    question: "Dead Cat Bounce",
                    answer: "A temporary recovery in prices following a significant decrease."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized",
                    answer: "Decentralization refers to a system in which nodes or actors work in a distributed fashion to achieve a global goal without relying on a central authority."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized Applications (DApps)",
                    answer: "Applications that run on a decentralized network, avoiding a single point of failure."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized Autonomous Initial Coin Offerings (DAICO)",
                    answer: "A decentralized funding method combining ideas from DAOs and ICOs, proposed by Vitalik Buterin, allowing backers to vote for fund returns if conditions are unmet."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAO)",
                    answer: "Organizations managed through rules encoded in smart contracts, without traditional central governance."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized Exchange (DEX)",
                    answer: "A peer-to-peer platform for buying and selling cryptocurrency without a central intermediary."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decryption",
                    answer: "The process of transforming encrypted data back into its original, readable form."
                },
                {
                    question: "DeFi",
                    answer: "DeFi, or decentralized finance, is an ecosystem of financial tools built on blockchain, offering open and permissionless alternatives to traditional financial services."
                },
                {
                    question: "Deflation",
                    answer: "A reduction in the general level of prices in an economy, or a monetary policy where the supply of currency or assets is fixed, like Bitcoin."
                },
                {
                    question: "Delegated Proof-of-Stake (dPOS)",
                    answer: "A consensus mechanism where users vote for delegates who produce blocks, with votes proportional to their stake, improving efficiency and reducing environmental impact."
                },
                {
                    question: "Depth Chart",
                    answer: "A graph showing buy (bids) and sell (asks) requests on a chart based on limit orders, indicating where transactions are likely to occur."
                },
                {
                    question: "Derivative",
                    answer: "A contract deriving its value from the performance of an underlying asset, index, or interest rate."
                },
                {
                    question: "Derivatives Market",
                    answer: "A public market for trading derivatives, such as futures contracts or options, based on other cryptocurrency assets."
                },
                {
                    question: "Deterministic Wallet",
                    answer: "A wallet that derives keys from a seed, allowing users to back up and restore the wallet using the same seed. *See Hierarchical Deterministic Wallet (HD Wallet)."
                },
                {
                    question: "Difficulty",
                    answer: "A relative measure of how difficult it is to discover a new block. In Bitcoin, difficulty adjusts periodically based on the network's hashing power."
                },
                {
                    question: "Digital Commodity",
                    answer: "An intangible asset transferred electronically that holds a certain value."
                },
                {
                    question: "Digital Currency",
                    answer: "A type of currency available only in digital form, allowing for instantaneous transactions and borderless ownership transfer."
                },
                {
                    question: "Digital Identity",
                    answer: "Digital representations and storage of personal information, such as name and address. On the blockchain, digital identity can be decentralized and used securely for identity verification."
                },
                {
                    question: "Digital Signature",
                    answer: "A digital code generated by key encryption that verifies the contents of an electronically transmitted document and the sender's identity."
                },
                {
                    question: "Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG)",
                    answer: "A data structure built in a single direction that does not repeat, commonly used in blockchain and cryptocurrency projects."
                },
                {
                    question: "Dildo in crypto terms",
                    answer: "A slang term referring to a long green or red bar on a price chart, representing significant price changes of a cryptocurrency."
                },
                {
                    question: "Distributed Consensus",
                    answer: "A collective agreement by nodes in a network, enabling decentralized operation without a central authority."
                },
                {
                    question: "Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) Attack",
                    answer: "A cyber-attack where a system is overloaded with requests, disrupting legitimate access and making services unavailable."
                },
                {
                    question: "Distributed Ledger",
                    answer: "A ledger where data is stored across a decentralized network of nodes, which may or may not involve cryptocurrency."
                },
                {
                    question: "Distributed Ledger Technology (DLT)",
                    answer: "The technology behind distributed ledgers, often used in enterprise applications for decentralized data storage and sharing."
                },
                {
                    question: "Distributed Network",
                    answer: "A network where processing power and data are spread across nodes, with no centralized authority."
                },
                {
                    question: "Dolphin in cryptocurrency",
                    answer: "A person who owns a moderate amount of cryptocurrency, between a fish/minnow and a whale in terms of holdings."
                },
                {
                    question: "Dominance",
                    answer: "An index comparing the market capitalization of Bitcoin (BTC Dominance) to the total market cap of all cryptocurrencies."
                },
                {
                    question: "Double Spending",
                    answer: "A fraudulent situation where the same sum of money is spent more than once."
                },
                {
                    question: "Dump",
                    answer: "To sell off all your cryptocurrency holdings."
                },
                {
                    question: "Dumping",
                    answer: "The collective selling off of cryptocurrencies, leading to a downward price movement."
                },
                {
                    question: "Dust Transactions",
                    answer: "Tiny transactions that flood and slow the network, often created deliberately to disrupt operations."
                },
                {
                    question: "Dusting Attack",
                    answer: "A scam where tiny amounts of cryptocurrency are sent to wallets, allowing scammers to track transactions and identify wallet owners."
                },
                {
                    question: "DYOR",
                    answer: "An acronym for 'Do Your Own Research,' a reminder to verify information independently instead of relying solely on others."
                }]
        },

        {
            "E": [
                {
                    question: "ELI5",
                    answer: "Stands for 'Explain Like I’m 5,' an explanation so simple that even a five-year-old can understand it."
                },
                {
                    question: "Enterprise Ethereum Alliance (EEA)",
                    answer: "A group of Ethereum developers, startups, and large corporations working together to commercialize and use Ethereum for business applications."
                },
                {
                    question: "Emission",
                    answer: "The speed at which new coins are created and released, also known as Emission Curve, Emission Rate, or Emission Schedule."
                },
                {
                    question: "ERC-20",
                    answer: "A token standard for Ethereum defining rules for implementing tokens, including transfer between addresses and data access."
                },
                {
                    question: "ERC-721",
                    answer: "A token standard for non-fungible Ethereum tokens, introduced in 2017, enabling unique tradeable tokens on the Ethereum blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Escrow",
                    answer: "A contractual arrangement where a third party manages funds or documents for transacting parties, disbursing them when agreed conditions are met. Blockchain can automate this via smart contracts."
                },
                {
                    question: "Ether",
                    answer: "The currency used in Ethereum to incentivize the execution of operations and power decentralized applications."
                },
                {
                    question: "Ethereum Improvement Proposal (EIP)",
                    answer: "Standards for the Ethereum platform, including protocol specifications, client APIs, and contract standards."
                },
                {
                    question: "Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM)",
                    answer: "A Turing-complete virtual machine that executes smart contracts and maintains consensus on the Ethereum blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Exchange",
                    answer: "Businesses that allow customers to trade cryptocurrencies for fiat money or other cryptocurrencies."
                },
                {
                    question: "Exchange Traded Fund (ETF)",
                    answer: "A security that tracks a basket of assets, including stocks and cryptocurrencies, and can be traded like a single stock."
                }]
        },

        {
            "F": [
                {
                    question: "Faucet",
                    answer: "A reward system, often on websites or apps, offering cryptocurrency rewards for completing specific tasks, commonly used to promote new altcoins."
                },
                {
                    question: "Fiat",
                    answer: "Legal tender backed by a central government, such as physical cash or electronic representations like bank credit."
                },
                {
                    question: "Fiat-Pegged Cryptocurrency",
                    answer: "A blockchain-based coin or token linked to a government-issued currency, maintaining a guaranteed cash value in reserves."
                },
                {
                    question: "Fish in cryptocurrency",
                    answer: "A small-scale cryptocurrency holder, often at the mercy of market movements caused by whales. *See Dolphin and Whale."
                },
                {
                    question: "Flippening",
                    answer: "A scenario where the total market capitalization of Ethereum surpasses that of Bitcoin, a hope held by Ethereum supporters."
                },
                {
                    question: "Flipping",
                    answer: "An investment strategy of buying an asset with the intent to resell it for a profit, often shortly after purchase. In ICOs, flipping refers to quickly reselling tokens once they are listed on exchanges."
                },
                {
                    question: "FOMO",
                    answer: "An acronym for 'Fear of Missing Out,' describing apprehension over missing a potentially profitable investment opportunity. *See JOMO."
                },
                {
                    question: "Fork (Blockchain)",
                    answer: "A blockchain split that creates an alternate version, leading to two blockchains running simultaneously, such as Ethereum and Ethereum Classic."
                },
                {
                    question: "Fork (Software)",
                    answer: "When developers take existing source code from one project and modify it to create a new project, like Litecoin, which forked from Bitcoin."
                },
                {
                    question: "FUD",
                    answer: "An acronym for 'Fear, Uncertainty, and Doubt,' a strategy to spread negative or misleading information to influence perception of cryptocurrencies."
                },
                {
                    question: "FUDster",
                    answer: "Someone who spreads FUD (Fear, Uncertainty, and Doubt) to influence perceptions of cryptocurrencies or markets."
                },
                {
                    question: "Full Node",
                    answer: "A node that downloads an entire blockchain’s history to observe and enforce its rules."
                },
                {
                    question: "Fundamental Analysis (FA)",
                    answer: "A method of evaluating the value of an asset by researching its technology, team, growth prospects, and other factors, often used in value investing."
                },
                {
                    question: "Futures",
                    answer: "Standardized legal agreements to buy or sell an asset at a predetermined price and date in the future, differing from customizable forward contracts."
                }]
        },

        {
            "G": [
                {
                    question: "Gains",
                    answer: "An increase in value or profit from an investment."
                },
                {
                    question: "Gas on Ethereum",
                    answer: "A unit that measures the computational effort required to perform transactions, execute smart contracts, or launch DApps on the Ethereum network. It is considered the 'fuel' of the Ethereum ecosystem."
                },
                {
                    question: "Gas Limit",
                    answer: "The maximum amount of gas a user is willing to spend on an Ethereum transaction."
                },
                {
                    question: "Gas Price",
                    answer: "The price a user is willing to pay for gas in an Ethereum transaction. Higher gas prices incentivize miners to prioritize the transaction."
                },
                {
                    question: "Genesis Block",
                    answer: "The first block of data processed and validated to form a new blockchain, often referred to as block 0 or block 1."
                },
                {
                    question: "Gold-Backed Cryptocurrency",
                    answer: "A coin or token representing a value of gold, such as one physical gram of gold being equal to one token, with the gold stored securely."
                },
                {
                    question: "Graphical Processing Unit (GPU)",
                    answer: "Commonly known as a graphics card, it is a computer chip that creates 3D images but is also efficient for mining cryptocurrencies."
                },
                {
                    question: "Group Mining",
                    answer: "Another term for a Mining Pool, where multiple participants combine resources to mine cryptocurrencies together."
                },
                {
                    question: "Gwei",
                    answer: "The denomination used to define the cost of gas in Ethereum transactions, with 1 Gwei being a small fraction of 1 Ether."
                }]
        },

        {
            "H": [
                {
                    question: "Hacking",
                    answer: "The unauthorized use of a computer to manipulate another computer or system."
                },
                {
                    question: "Halving",
                    answer: "An event in Bitcoin where the reward for mining a block is halved, occurring every 210,000 blocks."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hard Cap",
                    answer: "The maximum amount of funds an ICO will raise. Once the hard cap is reached, no additional funds are collected."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hard Fork (Blockchain)",
                    answer: "A type of protocol change that validates previously invalid transactions and invalidates previously valid ones, splitting a cryptocurrency into two blockchains. Examples include Bitcoin and Bitcoin Cash."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hash",
                    answer: "The process of applying a hash function to input data, producing a fixed-length output that is unique and irreversible without a cipher."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hash Function",
                    answer: "A function used to map data of arbitrary size to a fixed size. *See Cryptographic Hash Function."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hash Power / Hash Rate",
                    answer: "The computing power used by a network to perform hashing operations, measured in units like kH/s, MH/s, or TH/s."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hierarchical Deterministic Wallet (HD Wallet)",
                    answer: "A wallet using the HD protocol to generate multiple crypto-wallets from a single master seed, often derived from 12 mnemonic phrases."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hidden Cap",
                    answer: "An undisclosed limit on the amount of money a project accepts during an ICO, allowing smaller investors to participate without large investors dominating."
                },
                {
                    question: "HODL",
                    answer: "A passive investment strategy of holding onto cryptocurrencies long-term regardless of market changes. The term originated from a typo and now stands for 'Hold On for Dear Life.'"
                },
                {
                    question: "Hosted Wallet",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency wallet managed by a third-party service."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hot Storage",
                    answer: "The online storage of private keys for quicker access to cryptocurrencies. *See Cold Storage."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hot Wallet",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency wallet connected to the internet for hot storage, as opposed to offline cold wallets. *See Cold Wallet."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hybrid PoW/PoS",
                    answer: "A consensus mechanism combining proof-of-work (PoW) for security and proof-of-stake (PoS) for governance and energy efficiency."
                },
                {
                    question: "Hyperledger (Hyperledger Foundation)",
                    answer: "An open-source blockchain project founded by the Linux Foundation in 2015 to develop blockchain-related tools and distributed ledgers."
                }]
        },

        {
            "I": [
                {
                    question: "Immutable",
                    answer: "A property of data or records that cannot be altered after being created, ensuring integrity over time."
                },
                {
                    question: "Inflation",
                    answer: "A general increase in prices and a decrease in the purchasing value of money."
                },
                {
                    question: "Initial Coin Offering (ICO)",
                    answer: "A crowdfunding method using cryptocurrencies to raise capital for startups or projects, often criticized for scams and market manipulation."
                },
                {
                    question: "Initial Exchange Offering (IEO)",
                    answer: "A fundraising event conducted on a cryptocurrency exchange's platform, as opposed to an ICO where the project team directly raises funds."
                },
                {
                    question: "Initial Token Offering (ITO)",
                    answer: "A token sale focused on offering tokens with utility in a software ecosystem, similar to an ICO but often emphasizing intrinsic utility."
                },
                {
                    question: "Initial Bounty Offering (IBO)",
                    answer: "A process where new cryptocurrency is distributed to individuals who complete tasks, such as translations or marketing, instead of buying tokens."
                },
                {
                    question: "Instamine",
                    answer: "A period shortly after launch when a large portion of mineable coins are quickly mined and distributed, often unevenly."
                },
                {
                    question: "Intermediary / Middleman",
                    answer: "A person or entity that facilitates agreements or transactions between two parties."
                }]
        },

        {
            "J": [
                {
                    question: "JOMO",
                    answer: "An acronym for 'Joy of Missing Out,' often used by individuals who are content not participating in cryptocurrencies, especially during downturns."
                }]
        },

        {
            "K": [
                {
                    question: "KYC",
                    answer: "Short for 'Know Your Customer,' it refers to verifying a customer's identity in compliance with anti-money laundering regulations."
                }]
        },

        {
            "L": [
                {
                    question: "Lambo",
                    answer: "Short for Lamborghini, it symbolizes wealth from cryptocurrency investments and is used in phrases like 'When Lambo' referring to future price increases."
                },
                {
                    question: "Ledger",
                    answer: "A record of financial transactions that is immutable and can only be appended with new transactions."
                },
                {
                    question: "Leverage",
                    answer: "A loan provided by a broker during margin trading to increase the availability of funds for trades."
                },
                {
                    question: "Lightning Network",
                    answer: "A second-layer payment protocol for blockchains designed to enable fast, scalable transactions, proposed as a solution to Bitcoin's scalability issues."
                },
                {
                    question: "Limit Order / Limit Buy / Limit Sell",
                    answer: "Orders placed by traders to buy or sell cryptocurrency at a specific price, differing from market orders which execute at the best available price."
                },
                {
                    question: "Liquidity",
                    answer: "The ease with which a cryptocurrency can be bought or sold without significantly impacting its market price."
                },
                {
                    question: "Long",
                    answer: "A position where you buy a cryptocurrency expecting to sell it later at a higher price for profit."
                }]
        },

        {
            "M": [
                {
                    question: "Mainnet",
                    answer: "An independent blockchain running its own network and technology, where its native tokens are in use, as opposed to testnets or hosted blockchains."
                },
                {
                    question: "Market",
                    answer: "An arena, online or offline, where commercial dealings are conducted. The 'crypto market' refers to the cumulative cryptocurrencies and projects operating within the industry."
                },
                {
                    question: "Market Capitalization / Market Cap / MCAP",
                    answer: "The total capitalization of a cryptocurrency’s price, used to rank the relative size of cryptocurrencies. *See Circulating Supply."
                },
                {
                    question: "MarketOrder / Market Buy / Market Sell",
                    answer: "A purchase or sale of a cryptocurrency at the current best available price on an exchange. Market orders are executed as buyers and sellers are willing to trade."
                },
                {
                    question: "MarginCall",
                    answer: "When an investor’s account value falls below the required maintenance amount, prompting the broker to demand additional funds or securities to meet the minimum required balance."
                },
                {
                    question: "Margin Trading",
                    answer: "A practice where traders borrow funds from a broker to trade cryptocurrencies, using the assets as collateral. Positions include 'Margin Bear' (short) and 'Margin Bull' (long)."
                },
                {
                    question: "Masternodes",
                    answer: "Servers with additional functionalities like anonymizing transactions, clearing transactions, and governance. Popularized by Dash, masternodes reward operators for maintaining blockchain services."
                },
                {
                    question: "Max Supply",
                    answer: "The best approximation of the maximum number of coins that will ever exist for a cryptocurrency. *See Circulating Supply and Total Supply."
                },
                {
                    question: "MerkleTree",
                    answer: "A cryptographic tree structure where each leaf node is labeled with the hash of a data block, and non-leaf nodes are labeled with the hash of their child nodes. Merkle Trees enable efficient and secure blockchain verification."
                },
                {
                    question: "MicroBitcoin (uBTC)",
                    answer: "One millionth of a bitcoin (0.000001 BTC). Not to be confused with a Bitcoin fork."
                },
                {
                    question: "Microtansaction",
                    answer: "A business model for very small payments in exchange for digital goods or services, like ebook pages or in-game items."
                },
                {
                    question: "Mineable",
                    answer: "Refers to cryptocurrencies that reward miners with newly-created coins for processing transactions and creating blocks. *'Not Mineable' cryptocurrencies generate new coins through other mechanisms, like staking."
                },
                {
                    question: "Miners",
                    answer: "Contributors to a blockchain who participate in the mining process. They can range from hobbyists to large-scale operations."
                },
                {
                    question: "Mining",
                    answer: "The process of adding blocks to a blockchain, verifying transactions, and creating new cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin."
                },
                {
                    question: "MiningContract",
                    answer: "Another term for cloud mining, where users rent or invest in mining capacity online."
                },
                {
                    question: "MiningPool",
                    answer: "A setup where multiple miners combine computing power to increase competitiveness in finding blockchain blocks. Rewards are split among participants."
                },
                {
                    question: "MiningReward",
                    answer: "The reward for contributing computing resources to process transactions, typically a mix of newly minted coins and transaction fees."
                },
                {
                    question: "MiningRig",
                    answer: "A computer used for mining cryptocurrencies. It can be a dedicated mining machine or a multipurpose computer mining part-time."
                },
                {
                    question: "Minnow",
                    answer: "Another term for a Fish, referring to someone who holds small amounts of cryptocurrency."
                },
                {
                    question: "Mixing Service",
                    answer: "Also called a tumbler, a service that mixes identifiable cryptocurrency transactions with unrelated ones to enhance privacy and anonymity."
                },
                {
                    question: "Mnemonics",
                    answer: "Memory aids that use systems like letters or associations to help recall information. *See Mnemonic Phrase."
                },
                {
                    question: "Mnemonic Phrase",
                    answer: "A sequence of words used to access or restore cryptocurrency assets, commonly used in HD wallets. It must be kept secret."
                },
                {
                    question: "Money Transmitter/Money Transfer License",
                    answer: "In the U.S., it is a license for businesses offering money transfer services or payment instruments, including cryptocurrency, under Money Service Businesses (MSBs)."
                },
                {
                    question: "Moon",
                    answer: "A situation where a cryptocurrency's price experiences a continuous upward trend, often referenced as 'When moon' in crypto communities."
                },
                {
                    question: "Moving Average Convergence Divergence (MACD)",
                    answer: "A technical analysis method showing the relationship between two price moving averages, calculated by subtracting the 26-day EMA from the 12-day EMA."
                },
                {
                    question: "Mt. Gox",
                    answer: "One of the first fiat-to-Bitcoin exchanges, shut down in 2014 after losing approximately 850,000 Bitcoin. Originally created as a trading platform for 'Magic: The Gathering' cards."
                },
                {
                    question: "Multi-Signature (Multi-sig)",
                    answer: "An added security feature requiring more than one key to authorize a cryptocurrency transaction."
                }]
        },

        {
            "N": [
                {
                    question: "Network",
                    answer: "The collection of all nodes participating in the operation of a blockchain at any given time."
                },
                {
                    question: "Node",
                    answer: "A participant in the blockchain network that maintains a copy of the ledger."
                },
                {
                    question: "No-coiner",
                    answer: "Someone who does not own any cryptocurrency and often believes cryptocurrency will fail."
                },
                {
                    question: "Non-custodial",
                    answer: "A setup where private keys are held directly by the user, rather than by a third party. *See Custodial."
                },
                {
                    question: "Nonce",
                    answer: "An arbitrary number generated during mining to create a unique hash for a block."
                }]
        },

        {
            "O": [
                {
                    question: "Off-Ledger Currency",
                    answer: "Currency created outside of a blockchain ledger but still accepted or used."
                },
                {
                    question: "Offline Storage",
                    answer: "Storing cryptocurrencies in systems not connected to the internet, enhancing security. *See Online Storage."
                },
                {
                    question: "On-Ledger Currency",
                    answer: "Currency that is minted and used directly on a blockchain ledger, such as Bitcoin."
                },
                {
                    question: "Online Storage",
                    answer: "Storing cryptocurrencies in internet-connected systems for convenience but with increased risk. *See Offline Storage."
                },
                {
                    question: "One Cancels The Other Order (OCO)",
                    answer: "Two simultaneous cryptocurrency orders where the execution of one cancels the other."
                },
                {
                    question: "Open/Close",
                    answer: "The opening and closing prices of a cryptocurrency within a specific time frame. These terms are more common in traditional markets with fixed trading hours."
                },
                {
                    question: "Open Source",
                    answer: "Software released under a license allowing users to study, modify, and distribute it freely, aligning with the philosophy of sharing knowledge for the greater good."
                },
                {
                    question: "Option",
                    answer: "A contract granting the right, but not the obligation, to buy or sell an asset at a specified price by a certain date."
                },
                {
                    question: "Options Market",
                    answer: "A public market for trading options contracts to buy or sell cryptocurrencies at a specific strike price on or before a given date."
                },
                {
                    question: "Oracles",
                    answer: "Agents that verify and provide real-world data to smart contracts for their execution under predefined conditions."
                },
                {
                    question: "Orphan",
                    answer: "A valid block not part of the main blockchain, often due to simultaneous block creation or an attack."
                },
                {
                    question: "Overbought",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency considered overbought when its price rises excessively without justification, often followed by selling."
                },
                {
                    question: "Oversold",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency considered oversold when its price drops excessively without justification, often followed by buying."
                },
                {
                    question: "Over The Counter (OTC)",
                    answer: "Cryptocurrency trades conducted privately, outside of exchanges, often for large amounts or in jurisdictions with restricted exchanges."
                }]
        },

        {
            "P": [
                {
                    question: "Pair",
                    answer: "A trade between two cryptocurrencies, such as BTC/ETH."
                },
                {
                    question: "Paper Wallet",
                    answer: "A physical document containing private keys or seed phrases for cryptocurrency storage."
                },
                {
                    question: "Peer to Peer (P2P)",
                    answer: "Decentralized interactions where tasks or transactions are distributed directly between participants in a network."
                },
                {
                    question: "Permissioned Ledger",
                    answer: "A ledger with access restrictions, allowing only authorized users or organizations to access its data."
                },
                {
                    question: "Phishing",
                    answer: "A scam where someone pretends to be a trusted institution or person to trick users into revealing sensitive information like passwords or banking details."
                },
                {
                    question: "Platform",
                    answer: "On CoinMarketCap, it refers to the parent blockchain of tokens. It can also a cryptocurrency exchange where trading takes place."
                },
                {
                    question: "Ponzi Scheme",
                    answer: "A fraudulent investment scheme where returns are paid to earlier investors using funds from newer investors."
                },
                {
                    question: "Portfolio",
                    answer: "A collection of cryptocurrencies or crypto assets held by an individual, company, or financial institution."
                },
                {
                    question: "Pre-mine",
                    answer: "The creation of some or all of a coin’s supply before its public launch, often for crowdfunding or marketing purposes."
                },
                {
                    question: "Pre-sale",
                    answer: "A sale held before an ICO is made available to the general public for funding."
                },
                {
                    question: "Private Key / Secret Key",
                    answer: "A code used in asymmetric-key encryption, paired with a public key, to decrypt information and authorize transactions."
                },
                {
                    question: "Proof-of-Authority (PoA)",
                    answer: "A blockchain consensus mechanism that uses identity as a stake, enabling fast transactions."
                },
                {
                    question: "Proof-of-Burn (PoB)",
                    answer: "A blockchain consensus mechanism where coins are 'burned' (sent to an unspendable address) to verify cost and improve energy efficiency."
                },
                {
                    question: "Proof-of-Developer (PoD)",
                    answer: "Verification that proves a real developer created a cryptocurrency to prevent anonymous developers from disappearing with raised funds."
                },
                {
                    question: "Proof-of-Stake (PoS)",
                    answer: "A blockchain consensus mechanism where block creators are chosen based on random selection and the amount or age of staked coins. *See Proof-of-Work."
                },
                {
                    question: "Proof-of-Work (PoW)",
                    answer: "A blockchain consensus mechanism where miners solve computational puzzles to validate transactions and create new blocks. *See Proof-of-Stake."
                },
                {
                    question: "Protocol",
                    answer: "A set of rules governing network interactions, including consensus, transaction validation, and participation on a blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Pseudonymous",
                    answer: "Operating under a false name, such as 'Satoshi Nakamoto.'"
                },
                {
                    question: "Public Address",
                    answer: "A cryptographic hash of a public key, used as an address for receiving payments."
                },
                {
                    question: "Public Blockchain",
                    answer: "A blockchain that anyone can access and participate in."
                },
                {
                    question: "Pump and Dump (P&D) Scheme",
                    answer: "A form of fraud where a cryptocurrency’s price is artificially inflated with false statements to sell it at a higher price."
                }]
        },

        {
            "Q": [
                {
                    question: "QR Code",
                    answer: "A machine-readable black-and-white graphic used to share information, such as wallet addresses in cryptocurrency."
                }]
        },

        {
            "R": [
                {
                    question: "Raiden Network",
                    answer: "An off-chain scaling solution for Ethereum, enabling near-instant, low-fee, and scalable payments. Similar to Bitcoin’s Lightning Network."
                },
                {
                    question: "Replicated Ledger",
                    answer: "A copy of a distributed ledger shared among all participants in a cryptocurrency network."
                },
                {
                    question: "Rank",
                    answer: "The position of a cryptocurrency based on its market capitalization."
                },
                {
                    question: "REKT",
                    answer: "Shorthand for 'wrecked,' describing a significant loss in a trade."
                },
                {
                    question: "Reverse Indicator",
                    answer: "A person whose trading decisions are consistently wrong and can be used as a guide to avoid certain trades."
                },
                {
                    question: "Ring Signature",
                    answer: "A privacy feature that mixes inputs of multiple signers with the original sender to anonymize a transaction."
                },
                {
                    question: "ROI",
                    answer: "Short for 'Return on Investment,' it’s the ratio of net profit to the cost of an investment."
                },
                {
                    question: "Relative Strength Index (RSI)",
                    answer: "A momentum oscillator in technical analysis measuring price speed and change, indicating overbought conditions above 70 and oversold below 30."
                }]
        },

        {
            "S": [
                {
                    question: "Satoshi (SATS)",
                    answer: "The smallest unit of Bitcoin, equivalent to 0.00000001 BTC."
                },
                {
                    question: "Satoshi Nakamoto",
                    answer: "The pseudonymous creator or creators of Bitcoin. Their identity remains unknown."
                },
                {
                    question: "Scam",
                    answer: "A fraudulent or deceptive cryptocurrency or ICO designed to steal funds."
                },
                {
                    question: "Scrypt",
                    answer: "An alternative PoW algorithm to SHA-256, relying more on memory than CPU power to improve participation and energy efficiency."
                },
                {
                    question: "Second-Layer Solutions",
                    answer: "Technologies built on top of blockchains to enhance scalability and efficiency, such as Lightning Network and Plasma."
                },
                {
                    question: "Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)",
                    answer: "An independent U.S. federal agency responsible for enforcing securities laws, regulating the securities industry, and ensuring fair market practices."
                },
                {
                    question: "Seed",
                    answer: "A starting point used to derive keys for a deterministic wallet, usually presented as a series of words to back up or restore a wallet."
                },
                {
                    question: "Segregated Witness (SegWit)",
                    answer: "A Bitcoin Improvement Proposal (BIP) aimed at fixing transaction malleability by separating signature and block content, also reducing block sizes and enabling second-layer solutions."
                },
                {
                    question: "Selfish Mining",
                    answer: "A mining strategy where a miner withholds a discovered block, attempting to create the longest chain and invalidate others' blocks."
                },
                {
                    question: "Sell Wall",
                    answer: "A large limit order placed to sell a cryptocurrency at a specific price, often used to control market impressions and limit price increases."
                },
                {
                    question: "Side Chain",
                    answer: "A blockchain running in parallel to a primary chain, linked via a two-way peg, allowing independent operation with unique protocols."
                },
                {
                    question: "Simplified Payment Verification (SPV)",
                    answer: "A lightweight blockchain client that verifies transactions by downloading block headers and requesting proof of inclusion in the Merkle Tree."
                },
                {
                    question: "SHA-256",
                    answer: "A cryptographic hash function generating a 256-bit signature, used in Bitcoin's proof-of-work. It is part of the SHA-2 family developed by the NSA."
                },
                {
                    question: "Sharding",
                    answer: "A blockchain scaling solution that divides states and transaction history into partitions (shards) for parallel processing."
                },
                {
                    question: "Shilling",
                    answer: "The act of enthusiastically promoting a cryptocurrency or ICO project, often for personal gain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Shitcoin",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency with little to no potential value or utility."
                },
                {
                    question: "Short Selling (Short)",
                    answer: "A trading technique where an asset is borrowed and sold with the expectation of buying it back at a lower price for profit."
                },
                {
                    question: "Silk Road",
                    answer: "An online black market that operated on the dark web, known for accepting Bitcoin for transactions. It was shut down by the FBI."
                },
                {
                    question: "Smart Contract",
                    answer: "A self-executing contract on a blockchain that facilitates, verifies, or enforces agreements without third parties."
                },
                {
                    question: "Soft Cap",
                    answer: "The minimum amount an ICO aims to raise. If the soft cap isn't met, the ICO may be canceled. *See Hard Cap."
                },
                {
                    question: "Soft Fork (Blockchain)",
                    answer: "A blockchain protocol upgrade that makes previously valid transactions invalid, often requiring miners to upgrade their software. *See Hard Fork."
                },
                {
                    question: "Solidity",
                    answer: "The programming language used on Ethereum for developing smart contracts."
                },
                {
                    question: "Spoon (Blockchain)",
                    answer: "A meta-protocol creating a new blockchain that inherits token balances from an existing one, like the Tendermint hard spoon in 2018."
                },
                {
                    question: "Spot",
                    answer: "A transaction for immediate settlement of a cryptocurrency purchase or sale."
                },
                {
                    question: "Spot Market",
                    answer: "A public market where cryptocurrencies are traded for immediate settlement, as opposed to futures markets with later settlements."
                },
                {
                    question: "Stablecoin",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency designed for low volatility, often pegged to fiat currencies or backed by assets like gold."
                },
                {
                    question: "Staking",
                    answer: "The process of participating in a proof-of-stake system by locking tokens to validate blockchain transactions and earn rewards."
                },
                {
                    question: "Stale Block",
                    answer: "A block mined successfully but excluded from the current blockchain due to another block being added to the chain first."
                },
                {
                    question: "State Channel",
                    answer: "A second-layer scaling solution moving transactions off-chain, with participants later signing to record outcomes on the blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Symbol",
                    answer: "The ticker abbreviation representing a cryptocurrency, such as BTC for Bitcoin."
                }]
        },

        {
            "T": [
                {
                    question: "Taint",
                    answer: "The percentage of cryptocurrency in an account traceable to another account."
                },
                {
                    question: "Tangle",
                    answer: "A blockchain alternative developed by IOTA, using a directed acyclic graph (DAG) for quantum-resistant, non-repeating transaction paths."
                },
                {
                    question: "Testnet",
                    answer: "An alternative blockchain used by developers for testing purposes."
                },
                {
                    question: "Technical Analysis (TA)",
                    answer: "A market evaluation method using statistical analyses of price and volume trends to guide investment decisions."
                },
                {
                    question: "Think Long Term (TLT)",
                    answer: "An investment mindset focused on long-term horizons, typically months or years."
                },
                {
                    question: "This Is Gentlemen",
                    answer: "A phrase originating from a typo of 'This is it, gentlemen,' now used to introduce good news in the crypto community."
                },
                {
                    question: "Ticker",
                    answer: "An abbreviation uniquely identifying cryptocurrencies. *See Symbol."
                },
                {
                    question: "Timelock / Locktime",
                    answer: "A condition allowing a transaction to be processed only after a specific time or block on the blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Timestamp",
                    answer: "A record marking when a transaction occurred, including date and time, accurate to fractions of a second."
                },
                {
                    question: "Token",
                    answer: "A digital unit providing access to a crypto-economic system, often built for software development rather than as a store of value."
                },
                {
                    question: "Token Generation Event",
                    answer: "The moment when a cryptocurrency token is issued."
                },
                {
                    question: "Tokenize",
                    answer: "The process of converting real-world assets into digital tokens, enabling fractional ownership or digital representation."
                },
                {
                    question: "Tor",
                    answer: "Free software enabling anonymous communication by routing traffic through volunteer relays. Its name derives from 'The Onion Router.'"
                },
                {
                    question: "Total Supply",
                    answer: "The total number of coins currently in existence, excluding those verifiably burned. *See Circulating Supply and Max Supply."
                },
                {
                    question: "Trade Volume",
                    answer: "The total amount of a cryptocurrency traded over the last 24 hours."
                },
                {
                    question: "Transaction (TX)",
                    answer: "The act of transferring cryptocurrencies on a blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Transaction Fee",
                    answer: "A payment made to process a transaction on the blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Trustless",
                    answer: "A property of blockchain where participants do not need to trust each other for transactions to be enforced correctly."
                },
                {
                    question: "Tumbler",
                    answer: "Another term for a mixing service used to improve transaction privacy."
                },
                {
                    question: "Turing-Complet",
                    answer: "The ability of a machine to perform calculations that any programmable computer can execute, exemplified by the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM)."
                }]
        },

        {
            "U": [
                {
                    question: "Unconfirmed",
                    answer: "A state where a transaction has not yet been appended to the blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Unpermissioned Ledger",
                    answer: "Another term for a public blockchain."
                },
                {
                    question: "Unspent Transaction Output",
                    answer: "An output of a blockchain transaction that has not been spent and is available for use as an input in new transactions."
                },
                {
                    question: "UTC Time",
                    answer: "Coordinated Universal Time, the primary time standard for regulating clocks and time worldwide."
                }]
        },

        {
            "V": [
                {
                    question: "Validator",
                    answer: "A participant in a proof-of-stake (PoS) blockchain who validates blocks and earns rewards."
                },
                {
                    question: "Vanity Address",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency public address customized with specific letters or numbers chosen by the owner."
                },
                {
                    question: "Vaporware",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency project that is announced but never actually developed."
                },
                {
                    question: "Venture Capital",
                    answer: "Private equity funding provided to small, early-stage firms with high growth potential."
                },
                {
                    question: "Virgin Bitcoin",
                    answer: "A bitcoin that has never been spent."
                },
                {
                    question: "Volatility",
                    answer: "A measure of the price fluctuations of a cryptocurrency, often calculated using standard deviation or variance."
                },
                {
                    question: "Volume",
                    answer: "The amount of a cryptocurrency traded over a specific period, often used to predict future price trends and demand."
                }]
        },

        {
            "W": [
                {
                    question: "Wallet",
                    answer: "A secure digital wallet for storing, sending, and receiving cryptocurrency, categorized as hosted wallets or cold wallets."
                },
                {
                    question: "Wash Trade",
                    answer: "A market manipulation practice where investors simultaneously sell and buy the same cryptocurrency to create artificial activity."
                },
                {
                    question: "Watchlist",
                    answer: "A feature allowing users to track selected cryptocurrencies for updates and price changes."
                },
                {
                    question: "Weak Hands",
                    answer: "Investors prone to panic selling during price declines."
                },
                {
                    question: "Wei",
                    answer: "The smallest fraction of Ether, where 1 Ether equals 1,000,000,000,000,000,000 Wei."
                },
                {
                    question: "Whale",
                    answer: "An investor with a large amount of cryptocurrency, often with the ability to influence market prices."
                },
                {
                    question: "When Lambo",
                    answer: "A phrase used humorously to ask when significant profits will allow for the purchase of luxury items like a Lamborghini."
                },
                {
                    question: "When Moon",
                    answer: "A phrase asking when a cryptocurrency's price will experience a significant upward trend."
                },
                {
                    question: "Whitelist",
                    answer: "A list of participants who registered their intent to join an ICO or token sale."
                },
                {
                    question: "Whitepaper",
                    answer: "A document prepared by a cryptocurrency project to outline its vision, technical details, and roadmap for potential investors."
                }]
        },

        {
            "Y": [
                {
                    question: "YTD",
                    answer: "Year to Date."
                }]
        },
        
        {
            "Z": [
                {
                    question: "Zero Confirmation Transaction",
                    answer: "Another term for an unconfirmed transaction."
                },
                {
                    question: "Zero Knowledge Proof",
                    answer: "A cryptographic technique allowing one party to prove a transaction or event occurred without revealing private details."
                },
                {
                    question: "Zk-SNARKs",
                    answer: "Zero-Knowledge Succinct Non-Interactive Argument of Knowledge proofs enabling verification of information without revealing it or requiring interaction."
                }]
        }
    ]